Renaissance Architecture Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Renaissance Architecture Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 2004
Yale University Arts Library
47
141 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Renaissance architecture worldwide.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Renaissance architecture worldwide.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by country. Further divided by city or other local designation.
Architecture, Romanesque; Lantern slides; Reproductions; Slides
- General (Box 1)
- Austria (Box 1)
  - General Architects (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Fisher Von Erlach (Box 1)
  - Admont (Box 1)
  - Altenburg (Box 1)
  - Bruhl (Box 1)
  - Durnstein (Box 1)
  - Gottwerg (Box 2)
  - Graz (Box 2)
  - Heiligenkrenz (Box 2)
  - Herzogenburg (Box 2)
  - Innsbruck (Box 2)
  - Klosterneuburg (Box 2)
  - Innsbruck (Box 2)
  - Klosterneuburg (Box 2)
  - Kremunster (Box 2)
  - Melk-am-Donau (Box 2)
  - Neustift (Box 2)
  - Paura (Box 2)
  - S. Florian (Box 2)
  - Salzburg (Box 3)
    - Churches (Box 3)
      - Cathedral (Box 3)
      - Kollegien-Kirche (Box 3)
    - Palaces (Box 3)
      - Schloss-Mirabell (Box 3)
  - Schlierbach (Box 3)
  - Schlosshof (Box 3)
  - Seitenstetten (Box 3)
  - Spital-am-Phyrn (Box 3)
  - Stams (Box 3)
  - Vienna (Box 3)
    - Arches (Box 3)
    - Churches (Box 3)
      - St. Peter's (Box 3)
      - Karl Borromaus Kirche (Box 3)
      - Piaristenkirche (Box 3)
      - Salesianerinn-Enkirche (Box 3)
    - Government Buildings (Box 3)
      - Ministry of the Interior (Box 3)
    - Hospitals (Box 3)
    - Library (Box 3)
      - Hobibliothek (Court Library) (Box 3)
    - Monuments (Box 4)
    - Palaces (Box 4)
      - Various (Box 4)
      - Belvedere Palace (Box 4)
        - Upper Belvedere (Box 4)
        - Lower Belvedere (Box 4)
      - Hofburg Palace (Box 4)
      - Liechtenstein Palaces (Box 4)
      - Palace of the Prince Eugene (Box 4)
      - Palais Dain (Kinsky) (Box 4–5)
      - Schonbrun Palace (Box 5)
      - Schwarzenberg Palace (Box 5)
      - Starhemberg-Schonburg (Box 5)
      - Trautson Palace (Box 5)
    - Schools (Box 5)
      - Old University (Box 5)
    - Theatres (Box 5)
  - Wilhering (Box 5)
  - Wilten (Box 5)
  - Zwettl (Box 5)
- Belgium (Box 5)
  - Various (Box 5)
  - Antwerp (Box 5)
    - Various (Box 5)
    - Churches (Box 6)
      - S. Charles Borromee (Box 6)
    - Government Buildings (Box 6)
      - Hotel De Ville (Town Hall) (Box 6)
    - Houses (Box 6)
      - Ruben's House (Box 6)
  - Bruges (Box 6)
  - Brussels (Box 6)
  - Ghent (Box 6)
  - Leau (Box 6)
  - Liege (Box 6)
  - Malines (Box 6)
  - Namur (Box 6)
  - Parc (Box 6)
- Britain (Box 6)
  - General (Box 6)
  - Gardens (Box 6)
  - Houses (Box 6)
  - Ornament (Box 6–7)
  - Architects (Box 7)
    - Various (Box 7)
    - Adam, Robert (Box 7)
    - Barret, Robert (Box 7)
    - Lord Burlington (Box 7)
    - Chambers, Sir William (Box 7)
    - De Bruyn, Abraham (Box 7)
    - Evelyn, John (Box 7)
    - Gibbs, James (Box 7)
    - HalfPenny, W. (Box 7)
    - Harrington, Sir John (Box 8)
    - Hope, Thomas (Box 8)
    - Jones, Inigo (Box 8)
    - Kent, William (Box 8)
    - Langley, Batty (Box 8)
    - Leverton, Thomas (Box 8)
    - Morris, Robert (Box 8)
    - Paine, William (Box 8)
    - Plaw, John (Box 8)
    - Primatt, Stephen (Box 8)
    - Repton, Humphry (Box 8)
    - Shute, John (Box 8)
    - Soane, Sir John (Box 8)
    - Stuart & Revett (Box 8)
    - Ware, Isaac (Box 8)
    - Wren, Sir Christopher (Box 8–9)
    - Wrighte (Box 9)
  - Abington (Box 9)
  - Acton (Box 9)
  - Althirp, Northamptonshiere (Box 9)
  - Alton towers (Box 9)
  - Amesbury Abbey (Box 9)
  - Arbury (Box 9)
  - Ashburton, Devon (Box 9)
  - Aspley Guise (Box 9)
  - Aston Hall (Box 9)
  - Attingham Park (Box 9)
  - Audley End (Box 9)
  - Badminton (Box 9)
  - Balcarres (Box 9)
  - Barlsborough Hall (Box 9)
  - Barrington Court (Box 9)
  - Bath (Box 9)
    - Various (Box 9)
    - Baths (Box 9)
      - Grand Pump Room (Box 9)
      - King's Bath (Box 9)
    - Bridges (Box 9)
      - Pulteney Bridge (Box 9)
    - Government Buildings (Box 9)
      - Assembly Building (Box 9)
    - Hospitals (Box 9)
    - Hotels (Box 9)
      - Old Sydney Hotel (Box 9)
    - Houses (Box 9)
      - Prior Park (Box 9)
    - Prisons (Box 9)
    - Squares (Box 9)
      - Camden Crescent (Box 9)
      - Circus (Box 10)
      - Landsdown Crescent (Box 10)
      - Queen Square (Box 10)
      - Royal Crescent (Box 10)
  - Beckingham Hall (Box 10)
  - Beeston (Box 10)
  - Belton House (Box 10)
  - Berrington Hall (Herefordshire) (Box 10)
  - Birmingham (Box 10)
  - Blackheat (Box 10)
  - Blenheim Palace (Box 10)
    - Exteriors (Box 10)
    - Interior (Box 10)
  - Blickling Hall (Box 10)
    - Exterior (Box 10)
    - Interior (Box 10)
  - Bolsover Castle (Box 10)
  - Bolton (Box 10)
  - Bowden, Wiltshire (Box 10)
  - Bowood House (Box 10)
  - Bradbourne (Box 11)
  - Bradford-On-Avon (Box 11)
  - Bramhall (Box 11)
  - Bramham Park (Box 11)
  - Brasted Place (Box 11)
  - Brimscombe (Stroud Valley) (Box 11)
  - Bristol (Box 11)
  - Brocket Hall (Box 11)
  - Brocklesby, Lincolnshire (Box 11)
  - Burghley House (Box 11)
  - Burton Agnes (Box 11)
  - Cambridge (Box 11)
    - Senate House (Box 11)
    - Colleges (Box 11)
  - Canterbury (Box 11)
  - Castle Ashby (Box 11)
  - Castle Coole, Fermanagh, Ireland (Box 11)
  - Castle Howard (Box 11)
    - Exterior (Box 11)
    - Interior (Box 12)
    - Mausoleum (Monument) (Box 12)
  - Chastleton House (Box 12)
  - Chatsworth (Box 12)
    - Exterior (Box 12)
    - Interior (Box 12)
  - Chester (Box 12)
  - Chevening place (Box 12)
  - Chicheley Hall (Box 12)
  - Chichester (Box 12)
  - Chilham, Kent (Box 12)
  - Chipping Camden (Box 12)
  - Chiswick House (Box 12)
    - Plans & Elevations (Box 12)
    - Exterior (Box 12)
    - Interior (Box 12)
    - Gardens (Box 12)
  - Clandon Park (Box 12)
  - Claremont (Box 12)
  - Claydon House (Box 12)
  - Clivedon (Box 12)
  - Cobham Hall (Box 13)
  - Colchester (Box 13)
  - Coleshill House (Box 13)
    - Exterior (Box 13)
    - Interior (Box 13)
  - Comberton (Box 13)
  - Compton Wynyates (Box 13)
  - Corsham Court (Box 13)
  - Coventry (Box 13)
  - Cramborne Manor (Box 13)
  - Crewe House (Box 13)
  - Croome House (Box 13)
  - Croscombe (Box 13)
  - Croscombe (Box 13)
  - Daylesford, Worcestershire (Box 13)
  - Deedham (Box 13)
  - Deeping Fen (Box 13)
  - Derby (Box 13)
  - Ditchley House (Box 13)
  - Drayton House (Box 13)
  - Dublin (Box 13)
    - Government Buildings (Box 13)
      - City Hall (Box 13)
      - Custom's House (Box 13)
      - Parliament (Box 14)
    - Schools (Box 14)
  - Dudingston (Box 14)
  - Duncombe Park (Box 14)
  - Eastbury (Box 14)
  - Eastbury Manor House (Box 14)
  - Easton Neston (Box 14)
  - Edinburgh (Box 14)
    - Churches (Box 14)
    - Hospitals (Box 14)
    - Schools (Box 14)
    - Squares (Box 14)
  - Eltham Lodge (Box 14)
  - Fairford (Box 14)
  - Flint (Box 14)
  - Ffynone, Pembrokshire (Box 14)
  - Foremark (Box 14)
  - Fountain Hall (Box 14)
  - Frampton (Box 14)
  - Frogmore House (Box 14)
  - Glasgow (Box 14)
  - Glensford (Box 14)
  - Goodwood House (Box 14)
  - Gowen, Glam, Wales (Box 14)
  - Grasmere (Box 14)
  - Greenwich (Box 14)
    - S. Alfege (Box 14)
    - Greenwich Hospital (Box 14)
      - General Views (Box 14)
      - Painted Hall (Box 14)
      - Chapel (Box 15)
      - King Charles Block (Box 15)
      - King Willian Block (Box 15)
      - Queen Mary's Block (Box 15)
      - Queen's House (Box 15)
  - Grimsthorpe Castle (Box 15)
  - Groomsbridge Place (Box 15)
  - Hacheston (Box 15)
  - Haddon Hall (Box 15)
    - Exterior (Box 15)
    - Interior (Box 15)
  - Hagley Park (Box 15)
  - Ham House (Box 15)
  - Hamilton Place (Box 15)
  - Hamener Wood Lodge (Box 15)
  - Hampton (Box 15)
  - Hampton Court (Box 15)
    - Palace (Box 15)
  - Hampton Court Herefordshire (Box 15)
  - Hardwick Hall (Box 16)
  - Harewood House (Box 16)
  - Hatchlands (Box 16)
  - Hatch Court (Box 16)
  - Hatfield House (Box 16)
    - Exterior (Box 16)
    - Interior (Box 16)
  - Heaton Park (Box 16)
    - Exterior (Box 16)
    - Interior (Box 16)
  - Hereford (Box 16)
  - Holme Lacy (Box 16)
  - Hertforshire (Box 16)
  - Heveningham Hall (Box 16)
    - Exterior (Box 16)
    - Interior (Box 16)
  - Highnam Court (Box 16)
  - Hildersham (Box 16)
  - Hinton Admiral (Box 17)
  - Holkham Hall (Box 17)
  - Hopetown House (Box 17)
  - Houghton Hall (Box 17)
    - Exterior (Box 17)
    - Interior (Box 17)
  - Hursley Park (Box 17)
  - Ipswich (Box 17)
  - Kedleston Hall (Box 17)
    - Exterior (Box 17)
    - Interior (Box 17)
  - Kenwood, Hampstead (Box 17)
  - Kew, Surrey (Box 17)
  - King's Lynn (Box 17)
  - Kings Weston, Gloucestershire (Box 17)
  - Kingston Lacy (Box 17)
  - Kirby Hall, Northampshire (Box 17)
    - Exterior (Box 17–18)
    - Interior (Box 18)
  - Kirby Hall, Yorkshire (Box 18)
    - Exterior (Box 18)
    - Interior (Box 18)
  - Knole (Box 18)
  - Laccock Abbey (Box 18)
  - Lanhydrock (Box 18)
  - Lavenham, Suffolk (Box 18)
  - Layer Marney Tower (Box 18)
  - Laxton (Box 18)
  - Leasowes (Box 18)
  - Ledbury (Box 18)
  - Leeds (Box 18)
  - Lees Court, Kent (Box 18)
  - Leichester (Box 18)
  - Leominster, Herts (Box 18)
  - Leven's Hall (Box 18)
  - Lewisham (Box 18)
  - Linfield Old Place (Box 18)
  - Liverpool (Box 18)
  - Llangadfan, Montgomery Shire Walls (Box 18)
  - Llysbewydd (Box 18)
  - Londesburg (Box 18)
  - London (Box 18)
    - General (Box 18)
    - Plans (Box 18)
    - Planning (Box 18)
    - Views (Box 19)
    - General Bridges (Box 19)
    - Churches (Box 19)
      - Christ Church, Newgate St (Box 19)
      - Christ Church Spitalfields (Box 19)
      - S. Alban (Box 19)
      - S. Anne (Box 19)
      - S. Bride, Fleet Street (Box 19)
      - S. Clement-Danes (Box 19)
      - S. George (Box 19)
      - S. George, Hanover Square (Box 19)
      - S. George-in-the-East (Box 19)
      - S. John, Horselydown (Box 19)
      - S. John, Smith Square (Box 19)
      - S. Leonard Shoreditch (Box 19)
      - S. Martin's-in-the-Fields (Box 19)
      - S. Martin's Ludgate (Box 20)
      - S. Mary-at-Hill (Box 20)
      - S. Mary Le Bow (Box 20)
      - S. Mary Le Strand (Box 20)
      - S. Mary Woolnoth (Box 20)
      - S. Paul's Cathedral (Box 20)
        - Inigo Jones Rebuilding (Box 20)
        - Plans and Sections (Box 20)
        - Wren's Great Model Drawing (Box 20)
        - Exterior (Box 20)
        - Interior (Box 20)
      - S. Paul, Deptford (Box 20)
      - S. Stephen, Walbrook (Box 20)
      - S. Vedast Foster (Box 21)
    - Clubs (Box 21)
    - Gates (Box 21)
    - Government Buildings (Box 21)
      - Hall of the Brewers Co. (Box 21)
      - Home Office (Box 21)
      - Horse Guards (Box 21)
      - Somerset House (Box 21)
        - Exterior (Box 21)
        - Interior (Box 21)
      - Temple Bar (Box 21)
    - Hospitals (Box 21)
    - Houses (Box 21)
      - Albany (Box 21)
      - Arundel (Box 21)
      - Ashurnham house (Box 21)
      - 44 Berkeley House (Box 22)
      - Buckingham House (Box 22)
      - Burlington House (Box 22)
      - Carlton House (Box 22)
      - Chesterfield House (Box 22)
      - Clarendon House (Box 22)
      - Earl of Derby House (Box 22)
      - Eltham Lodge (Box 22)
      - Ely House (Box 22)
      - General Wade's House (Box 22)
      - Harewood House (Box 22)
      - Holland House (Box 22)
      - Lansdowne House (Box 22)
      - Lindsey House (Box 22)
      - Mansion House (Box 22)
      - Montague House (Box 22)
      - Shielburne House (Box 22)
      - Stone House (Box 22)
      - Trinity House (Box 22)
      - W.W. Wynn House (Box 22)
      - S. James Square Houses (Box 22)
    - Inns and Inns of Court (Box 22)
    - Markets (Box 22)
    - Monuments (Box 22)
    - Office Buildings (Box 23)
    - Palaces (Box 23)
      - Kensington Palace (Box 23)
      - Whitehall (Box 23)
      - Whitehall Banqueting House (Box 23)
    - Parks (Box 23)
      - Vauxhall Gardens (Box 23)
    - Prisons (Box 23)
    - Schools (Box 23)
    - Squares & Terraces (Box 23)
      - Adelphi Terrace (Box 23)
      - Covent Garden (Box 23)
      - Fitzroy Square (Box 23)
    - Theaters (Box 23)
  - Londonderry (Box 23)
  - Longford Castle (Box 23)
  - Longleat (Box 24)
  - Ludlow (Box 24)
  - Luntley (Box 24)
  - Luton (Box 24)
  - Macosquin (Box 24)
  - Marino (Box 24)
  - Melbourne, Derbyshire (Box 24)
  - Mereworth Castle, Kent (Box 24)
  - Milburn (Box 24)
  - Milton Abbas (Box 24)
  - Mitcham (Box 24)
  - Montacute (Box 24)
  - Moor Park (Box 24)
  - Newbury (Box 24)
  - Nonesuch Park (Box 24)
  - Northill (Box 24)
  - Nostell Priory (Box 24)
  - Nottingham (Box 24)
  - Osterley Park (Box 24)
    - Exterior (Box 24)
    - Interior (Box 24–25)
  - Oxford (Box 25)
    - Churches (Box 25)
      - St. Mary- The virgin (Box 25)
    - University Buildings and Colleges (Box 25)
      - All Soul's College (Box 25)
      - Bodelian Library (Box 25)
      - Branesone College (Box 25)
      - Christ Church College (Box 25)
      - Merton College (Box 25)
      - Oriel College (Box 25)
      - Queen's College (Box 25)
      - Radcliffe Library (Box 25)
      - Radcliffe Observatory (Box 25)
      - Sheldonian Theater (Box 25)
      - S. John's College (Box 25)
      - Trinity College (Box 25)
      - Wadham College (Box 25)
  - Pain's Hill (Box 25)
  - Parham (Box 25)
  - Pembridge (Box 25)
  - Penshurst Place (Box 25)
  - Petersham (Box 25)
  - Portsmouth (Box 25)
  - Prior Park (Box 26)
  - Ragley Hall (Box 26)
  - Ranelagh (Box 26)
  - Rochester (Box 26)
  - Rolvenden (Box 26)
  - Rothamstead (Box 26)
  - Rousham Hall (Box 26)
  - Rouhampton (Box 26)
  - Rushton Hall (Box 26)
  - Saffron Walden (Box 26)
  - Salisbury (Box 26)
  - Saltram House (Box 26)
  - Seaton Delaval (Box 26)
  - Selworthy (Box 26)
  - Sevennoaks (Box 26)
  - Shardeloes (Box 26)
  - Sheffield Place, Sussex (Box 26)
  - Shotover Park (Box 26)
  - Shrewsbury (Box 26)
  - Sizergh, Westmoreland (Box 26)
  - Smarden Turk Farm (Box 26)
  - Southgate Grove (Box 26)
  - Southill (Box 27)
  - Speke Hall (Box 27)
  - Spitalfields (Box 27)
  - Stamford (Box 27)
  - Stockton House (Box 27)
  - Stoke Bruerne (Box 27)
  - Stone (Box 27)
  - Stoneleigh Abbey (Box 27)
  - Stourhead, Wiltshire (Box 27)
    - Gardens (Box 27)
  - Stowe House (Box 27)
    - House (Box 27)
    - Gardens (Box 27)
    - Bridges (Box 27)
    - Temples (Box 27)
  - Strawberry Hill (Box 27)
    - Exterior (Box 27)
    - Interior (Box 27)
  - Sudbury Hall, Derbyshire (Box 28)
  - Sulgrave Manor (Box 28)
  - Swakeleys (Box 28)
  - Syon House (Box 28)
    - Exterior (Box 28)
    - Interior (Box 28)
  - Temple Newsam (Box 28)
  - Tenterden (Box 28)
  - Tetburg (Box 28)
  - Thaxted (Box 28)
  - Thorpe Hall, Cambridgeshire (Box 28)
  - Thorby Castle, Gloustershire (Box 28)
  - Tintinhull, Somerset (Box 28)
  - Tredegar Park (Box 28)
  - Twickenham (Box 28)
  - Tyttenhanger (Box 28)
  - Unstone Hall (Box 28)
  - Upminster (Box 28)
  - Vanbrugh Castle (Box 28)
  - Vyne (Box 28)
  - Wanstead House, Essex (Box 28)
  - Wallington Hall (Box 28)
  - Warwick (Box 28)
  - Welbeck Abbey (Box 28)
  - Wentworth Woodhouse (Box 28–29)
  - West Hogbourne (Box 29)
  - Westwood Park (Box 29)
  - West Wycombe (Box 29)
  - Willington (Box 29)
  - Wilton House (Box 29)
    - Exterior (Box 29)
    - Interior (Box 29)
  - Wimpole Hall (Box 29)
  - Winchester (Box 29)
  - Wingfield Manor, Derbyshire (Box 29)
  - Witham (Box 29)
  - Wollaton Hall (Box 29)
  - Wollerton Hall (Box 29)
  - Wolseley Hall (Box 29)
  - Woodchester (Box 29)
  - Woodhall Park (Box 29)
  - Woodstock (Box 29)
  - Woolwich (Box 29)
  - Worcester (Box 29)
  - Wrest Manor (Box 29)
  - Wrest Park, Bedfordshire (Box 29)
  - Wrightington Hall (Box 29)
  - Yelling, Huntingdonshire (Box 29)
  - York (Box 29)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 29–30)
  - Various (Box 30)
  - General Architects (Box 30)
    - Braunau (Broumov) (Box 30)
    - Breunau (Brevnov) (Box 30)
    - Chlumec (Box 30)
    - Frain (Box 30)
    - Gabel (Jablonne V) (Box 30)
    - Gutwasser (Dobra Voda) (Box 30)
    - Karlsbad (Karlovy Vary) (Box 30)
    - Kiritein (Krtiny) (Box 30)
    - Kladno (Box 30)
    - Kladraw (Kladruby) (Box 30)
    - Liblitz (Liblice) (Box 30)
    - Mlatz (Mladotice) (Box 30)
    - Prague (Box 30)
  - Maps & Plans (Box 30)
  - Churches (Box 30)
    - Kreuzherren-Kirche (Box 30)
    - Loreto (Box 30)
    - S. Ignatius (Box 30)
    - S. Johann Nepomuk am Feben (Box 31)
    - S. Kare Borromaus (Box 31)
    - S. Kiklas in Deraltstadt (Box 31)
    - S. Niklas der Kleinseite (Box 31)
      - Exterior (Box 31)
      - Interior (Box 31)
    - S. Thomas an Der Kleinseite (Box 31)
      - Palaces (Box 31)
    - Clam-Gallas (Box 31)
    - Czernin Palace (Box 31)
    - Hradschin Castle (Box 31)
    - Lobrowitz Palace (Box 31)
    - Schloss Troja (Box 32)
    - Waldstein Plalace (Box 32)
      - Schools (Box 32)
      - Villas (Box 32)
    - Schmirschitz (Smirice) (Box 32)
    - Woborischt (Oboriste) (Box 32)
    - Wodolka (Odolena Voda) (Box 32)
    - Woporan (Oporany) (Box 32)
- Denmark (Box 32)
  - Copenhagen (Box 32)
    - Various (Box 32)
    - Houses (Box 32)
    - Palaces (Box 32)
    - Squares (Box 32)
- France (Box 32)
  - General (Box 32)
    - Interior (Box 32)
    - Ornament (Box 32)
    - Recreation (Box 33)
    - Temporary Architects (Box 33)
  - Architects (Box 33)
    - French Academy Brize Designs (Box 33)
    - Boffrand, Germain (Box 33)
    - Boullee, Etienne Louis (Box 33)
    - Clerisseau, Charles Louis (Box 33)
    - Cochin, Charles (Box 33)
    - Chalgrin, Jean Francois (Box 33)
    - Desprez, L.J. (Box 33)
    - Du Cerceau, Jacques II, 1545-1614 (Box 33)
      - Charleval Chateau (Box 33)
      - Verneuil Chateau (Box 33)
    - Durand, J.N.L., 1760-1834 (Box 33–34)
    - Gondoin (Box 34)
    - Ledoux, Claude Nicolas, 1756-1806 (Box 34)
      - Various (Box 34)
      - Caisse D'Escomptie (Box 34)
      - Chaux (Box 34)
    - LePautre, Antoine, 1621-1691 (Box 34)
    - Leroy, M. (Box 34)
    - Mansart, J.H. (Box 34)
    - Meissonier (Box 34)
    - Orme, Philibert DeL' (Box 34)
    - Perrault, Claude (Box 34)
    - Perret de Chambery (Box 34–35)
    - Peyre, M.J. (Box 35)
    - Vauban, Sebastien, 1633-1707 (Box 35)
    - Vaudoyer, A.L.T. (Box 35)
  - Cities (Box 35)
    - Aix-En-Provence (Box 35)
    - Alencon (Box 35)
    - Ambroise (Box 35)
      - Chateau (Box 35)
    - Amiens (Box 35)
      - Theater (Box 35)
    - Anet (Box 35)
      - Chateau (Box 35)
        - Plans & Sections (Box 35)
        - Exterior (Box 35)
        - Interior (Box 35)
      - Chapel (Box 35)
    - Ancy-Le-Franc (Box 35)
    - Angers (Box 35)
    - Angouleme (Box 35)
    - Antibes (Box 35)
    - Arles (Box 35)
    - Arques (Box 35)
    - Arras (Box 35)
    - Asnieres (Box 35)
    - Assier (Box 35)
    - Autun (Box 35)
    - Auxerre (Box 35)
    - Avignon (Box 35)
    - Azay-le-Rideau (Box 35)
      - Chateau (Box 35)
        - Exterior (Box 35)
        - Interior (Box 36)
    - Bar-Le-Duc (Box 36)
    - Beaugency (Box 36)
      - Hotel De Ville (Box 36)
    - Beaumesnil (Box 36)
    - Beauvais (Box 36)
    - Bec-Hellouin (Box 36)
    - Bellevue (Box 36)
    - Benouville (Box 36)
    - Besancon (Box 36)
    - Betz (Box 36)
    - Blerancourt (Box 36)
    - Blois (Box 36)
      - Chateau (Box 36)
        - Mansard Project (Box 36)
          - Plans & Sections (Box 36)
          - Exterior (Box 36)
            - Wings of Francis (Box 36)
          - Stair Tower (Box 36)
          - Interior (Box 36–37)
            - Wing of Gastor d'Orleans (Box 37)
            - Hotel D'Alluye (Box 37)
            - S. Vincent (Box 37)
    - Bordeaux (Box 37)
      - Various (Box 37)
      - Archbishop's Palace (Box 37)
      - Bourse (Box 37)
      - Galerie Bordelaise (Box 37)
      - Hotel De Boissac (Box 37)
      - Place Royal (Box 37)
      - Theater (Box 37)
    - Bouflers (Box 37)
    - Bourges (Box 37)
      - Hotel L'Allement (Box 37)
    - Brissac (Box 37)
    - Bury (Box 37)
    - Caen (Box 37)
      - Hotel D'Ecoville (Box 37)
      - Notre Dame (Box 37)
      - S. Etienne (Box 37)
      - S. Pierre (Box 37)
    - Calais (Box 38)
    - Calvados (Box 38)
    - Cany (Box 38)
    - Carpentras (Box 38)
    - Chambery (Box 38)
    - Chambord (Box 38)
      - Chateau (Box 38)
        - Plans (Box 38)
        - Exterior (Box 38)
          - Various (Box 38)
          - Exterior Details (Box 38)
        - Interior (Box 38)
    - Chambourcy (Box 38)
      - Le Desert De Retz (Box 38)
      - Champs (Box 38)
    - Chanteloup (Box 38)
    - Chantilly (Box 39)
      - Chateau (Box 39)
        - Exterior & Gardens (Box 39)
        - Interior (Box 39)
        - Stables (Box 39)
    - Charenton (Box 39)
    - Charleval (Box 39)
    - Charleville (Box 39)
    - Chartres (Box 39)
    - Chaux (Box 39)
    - Chemaze (Box 39)
    - Chenonceaux (Box 39)
      - Chateau (Box 39)
        - Exterior (Box 39)
        - Interior (Box 39)
      - Chapel (Box 39)
    - Cheverny (Box 39)
      - Chateau (Box 39)
        - Exterior (Box 39)
        - Interior (Box 38)
    - Clagny (Box 38)
    - Compiegne (Box 38)
    - Chateau (Box 38)
      - Exterior (Box 39)
      - Interior (Box 39)
    - Conches (Box 39)
    - Coulommiers (Box 39)
    - Dampierre (Box 39)
    - Desert De Retz (Box 39)
    - Davron (Box 39)
      - Chateau Dewideville (Box 39)
    - Dijon (Box 39)
      - Hotel & Houses (Box 39)
    - Dreux (Box 40)
    - Duakerque (Box 40)
    - Ecouen (Box 40)
      - Chateau (Box 40)
    - Ermenonville (Box 40)
    - Eu (Box 40)
    - Evreux (Box 40)
    - Fere-En-Tardenis (Box 40)
    - Fontaine-Henri (Box 40)
    - Fontainebleau (Box 40)
      - Chateau (Box 40)
      - Exterior (Box 40)
        - Plans & Sections (Box 40)
          - Entrance Façade (Box 40)
        - Gardens (Box 40)
        - Interior (Box 40)
          - Chapel (Box 40)
          - Francois I Gallery (Box 40)
          - Henry II Gallery (Box 40)
          - Salon of Council (Box 40)
          - Salon De Maul (Queen's Bedroom) (Box 41)
          - Salon Louis XIII (Box 41)
          - Salle Francis I (Box 41)
          - Throne Room (Box 41)
    - Gaillon (Box 41)
      - Chateau (Box 41)
    - Gisors (Box 41)
    - Harfleur (Box 41)
    - Henrichmont (Box 41)
    - La Rochefoucauld (Box 41)
    - La Rochelle (Box 41)
    - La Tour D'Aigue (Box 41)
    - Le Havre (Box 41)
    - Le Lude (Box 41)
    - Le Mans (Box 41)
    - Lille (Box 41)
    - Limogenes (Box 41)
    - Lisieux (Box 41)
    - Loches (Box 41)
    - Louveciennes (Box 41)
    - Luneville (Box 41)
    - Lyon (Box 41)
    - Maintenon (Box 41)
    - Maisons-Laffitte (Box 42)
    - Malmaison (Box 42)
    - Marais (Box 42)
    - Marly (Box 42)
    - Marseilles (Box 42)
    - Maupertuis (Box 42)
    - Menars (Box 42)
    - Meudon (Box 42)
    - Mons (Box 42)
    - Montauban (Box 42)
    - Montlouis (Box 42)
    - Montmorency (Box 42)
    - Montpellier (Box 42)
    - Montresor (Box 42)
    - Nancy (Box 42)
      - Arches & Gates (Box 42)
      - Churches (Box 42)
        - Cathedral (Box 42)
        - Church of Bosecours (Box 42)
      - Government Buildings (Box 42)
        - Hotel De Ville (Box 42)
        - Palais Du Governement (Box 42)
      - Squares (Box 42)
        - Place Stanislas (Box 42)
    - Nevers (Box 43)
    - Neuilly (Box 43)
    - Nimes (Box 43)
    - Nogent-Les-Vierges (Box 43)
      - Chateau (Box 43)
    - Orleans (Box 43)
      - Cathedral of S. Croix (Box 43)
      - Houses (Box 43)
        - Agne Sorel (Box 43)
        - Francois I (Box 43)
        - Rue Du Tabourg (Box 43)
    - Paris (Box 43)
      - Plans (Box 43)
        - Du Cercau's Plan (Box 43)
        - Jailot's Plan (Box 43)
        - Merian, 1615 (Box 43)